beautythroughimperfection.com 2019-07-07

# Privacy Policy - Beauty through imperfection

## Who we are

Beauty Through Imperfection is a website belonging to Paula Rollo Media LLC. I believe it’s important to keep data safe and secure and if you are interested in learning what I do with the data that’s collected by this site, read on!

This blog is owned by me, Paula Rollo. I write from my heart and share a lot of opinions. I am not a medical professional, business expert, or even a parenting expert. All opinions and statements made here should be checked and verified by a expert before you make personal decisions for yourself or your family.

This blog is a personal blog written and edited by me. There are occasional guest bloggers and contributors who post here as well.

This blog accepts forms of cash advertising, sponsorship, paid insertions or other forms of compensation.

This blog abides by word of mouth marketing standards. We believe in honesty of relationship, opinion and identity. The compensation received may influence the advertising content, topics or posts made in this blog. That content, advertising space or post will be clearly identified as paid or sponsored content in keeping with the FTC guidelines of disclosure.

All opinions expressed on this blog are personal opinions. Any quotes, claims or representation of a product or service should be checked and verified with the provider, brand or company in question.

I am often compensated to provide opinion on products, services, websites and various other topics. Even though I receive compensation for my posts or advertisements, I always give honest opinions, findings, beliefs, or experiences on those topics or products. The views and opinions expressed on this blog are purely the my own. Any product claim, statistic, quote or other representation about a product or service should be verified with the manufacturer, provider or party in question.

As an Amazon Associate I earn from qualifying purchases. I am also an affiliate of other networks including but not limited to shareasale, awin and commission junction. I make money if you choose to make a purchase through my links.

I never promote things I do not believe in. I turn down many opportunities simply because they do not fit my blog or are not a product I feel comfortable talking about.

If you have any questions please contact me: paularollo at gmail.com

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection. So if you leave your name or email address, I’ll be storing that information. Your name will be displayed next to your comment. The good news is, if you don’t want to comment with your real name, or email you totally don’t have to. I’ve gotten more than a few fake names and fake emails, and I don’t mind it at all! Whatever you feel most comfortable with, is cool with me I just have to make sure you know that I’m collecting that data because that’s how comment sections on the internet work.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The [Gravatar service privacy policy is available here.](https://automattic.com/privacy/) After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

### Media

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

### Contact forms

If you use a contact form on my site, I will have access to and be storing the information you enter into my form to contact me. Seems, pretty straight forward, but the lawmakers wanted me to be sure I told you, so now you know.

### Cookies

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website. I have no way of accessing the information collected by these sites, and you would need to read their privacy policies for all the riveting details about how they may or may not be using your data.

### Analytics

I use Google Analytics to track visitors to my website. This shows me some handy information to help me make your experience on my website better, and is pretty standard. I see some geographical information (like how many visitors I’ve had from Houston, TX lately, but never anything creepy like your house number). Sometimes I’m also able to see how you found my website. Like through Pinterest, Twitter, Facebook or Google. This info helps me make sure I’m sharing my content where it needs shared. Your name isn’t held on there, but I am keeping data about visitors to my site’s behavior.

### Emails

You will find several places to sign up to receive a weekly newsletter from Beauty Through Imperfection or Quick Blogging Tips. The information you input to those forms will be stored by myself and my newsletter service, MailerLite. I will never send you spam and you will always have the opportunity to unsubscribe at any time, from the bottom of every email.

## How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

## What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

## Where we send your data

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service. I get a surprising number of spam comments a day (in the hundreds) and doing this allows me to keep my site functioning and not bogged down with literally tens of thousands of spammy (often pornographic) comments.

## Additional information

### How we protect your data

Listen, I’m a mom and a small business owner. I don’t have time to do anything sketchy with your data, nor do I have any desire to. I’m not gonna be giving your data out willy nilly and definitely would never ever sell it (that would be lame!). I am using your data to make my site function better and to make sure I give you the content you want. I protect it, by not being sleazy and selling it. Cool?

## Your contact information

Got questions about any of this? Me too. The law-making-people really did a number on us and I feel like I need a PHD in how the internet works in order to write this thing and assure you I’m not doing anything sketchy with your data.

But if you have questions for me about how the internet works, what the heck all this privacy policy stuff is about or maybe how to handle your toddler’s tantrums you can email me directly at: PaulaRollo@gmail.com

Full disclosure: I know more about tantrums than I understand all the nitty gritty about how internet works, but I’ll still try to help however I can!
